BORDIN PRASERTSUWAN Mechanical / Project / Piping Engineer

Career Summary

Bordin has about 6 years of an international and Thailand experience as Mechanical and Piping Engineer of petroleum, petrochemical, utility, data center facilities and industrial projects consisting of engineering design, material and cost management, and mechanical process.

I am also familiar in occupational, hygiene, safety and environment regulation and serve as a technical safety committee for CTCI (Thailand) co.,ltd for year 2011 to 2013.

I am also able to manage the project especially in petrochemical field. The Project management including budget estimation, project specification, schedule work, cost control, on field instruction and line check before handover.

I have a strong knowledge in PFD, P&ID as well as an equipment datasheet. I am also familiar with some international codex and standard such as ASME B31.3, ASTM, NFPA.

I have a good level in speaking, reading and writing English with the TOIEC score 830 (Aug'20th, 2012) and he has a beginning level in speaking, reading and writing Mandarin Chinese. He is familiar with Piping Design software e.g. PDMS, PDS, PMCS, AutoCAD, Navisworks and general software e.g. MS Project, MS office applications (Excel, Word, PowerPoint).

Date of Birth: 11th April 1982

Gender: Male

Nationality: Thai

Education:

Chiangmai University,

Thailand.

Qualification : Bachelor Degree in Mechanical Engineering

Contact:

Moblie : 081-9516653

085-9341997

E-mail;

<u>bordin.p@outlook.com</u> bangic@hotmail.com

Experience

Feb 2015 to Present

Penspen Co.,Ltd

Piping/Mechanical Engineer

- Responsible for detail design piping routing, pipe support design and overall layout checking for:
 - Provincial Gas Transmission Pipeline Project: PTT 28" Gas Transmission Pipieline from Wangnoi Ayudya to Nakhonsawan.
- Responsible for Piping and Mechanical Technical Consulting Project:

- SPX line: PTT Thaioil ESSO, Sriracha, Chonburi, Thailand. 12 in Pipeline transfer Paraxylene from Thailoil Tank Farm to PTT Berth#5
- Technical consulting for PTT for Piping routing detail design pipe stress report and constructability.
- Responsible for FEED project:
 - Yangon International Airport Jet A-1 Fuel Upgrad Project: Front End Engineering Design for Process and Firefighting piping.

May 2013 to Feb 2015

Vinythai Public Company Limited, Rayong, Thailand

Mechanical Engineer / Project Engineer

- Responsible for all modified and new project in ECH (Epichlorohydrin) Plant
 - Develops project objectives by reviewing project proposals and making plans including job method sheet and job safety analysis
 - Determines project schedule by studying project plan and specifications, budget estimation and calculating time requirements
 - Designs, sketch the piping routing and calculate the piping stress analysis if necessary, and give information for vendor and sub-contractor
 - Purchasing material and cost control by approving expenditures
 - Maintains project schedule by monitoring project progress, coordinating activities and resolving problems
 - Controls project plan by reviewing design, specifications, and plan and schedule changes
 - Maintains safe and clean working environment by enforcing procedures, rules, and regulations.
 - Checking and testing project before handover
 - Prepare project status report, analyzing and summarizing information
- Provide information support and advice to the organization
 - Provide internal document with scientific and technological advise to resolve technical problems or product quality problems.

May 2010 to April 2013

CTCI (Thailand), Bangkok, Thailand

Piping Stress Engineer

- Responsible for piping stress coding and input for stress analysis by using CEASAR II, job site surveying, problem solving, design and issue stress ISO drawing
 - IRPC Excalibur: IRPC, Rayong, Thailand.12 in and 6 in Ethylene piping -104 degree centigrade lines. (Aug 2012 – Nov 2012)
 - IRPC Phoenix: IRPC, Rayong, Thailand.6 in and 3 in. Ethylene piping -104 degree centigrade. (Nov 2013 – Apr 2012)

Piping Engineer

- Responsible for designing of piping system, issue ISO drawing, material take-off, Pipe support design and issue GA drawing for the following projects:
 - OPTC PTA: Pure Terephthalic Acid, OPTC, Taichung Industrial Park, Taiwan (Sep 2011 – July 2012)
 - PTT CWW: Comprehensive Waste Water Treatment Plant. PTT UT, Rayong, Thailand (Jun 2010 Oct 2010)
- Responsible for Material take-off, Pipe routing and valve MTO for bidding for the following projects:
 - Saudi Aramco Rabigh II CP1 Project, Saudi Arabia
 - Opal PP plant Project, India

Nov 2010 to May 2011

Jing Ding Engineering and Construction, Beijing, China

Piping Engineer

- Supply manpower for 30KTA NBR Project: JV btw Lanxess Germany and TSRC Taiwan, PDMS
- General Arrangement Piping Drawing Production for PTA (Pure Terephthalic Acid) revamping Project

Jan 2009 to Feb 2010

TSS CO., LTD, Samutprakan, Thailand

Mechanical Design Engineer

Design and consult for all building mechanical system as following:

- Fire Protection & Suppression System
- Ordinary and Computer Room Air Conditioning System
- Air-conditioning system for general area, Data Center & IT-room
- Sanitary system
- Cost Control & Produce BOQ

Project references:

- Thailand Post New Data Center Chaeng Wattana, Bangkok
- Institue of Director (IOD) Conference room and office, North Park, Bangkok
- CIMB Thai Data Center and DR Site, Suksawad, Samutprakran
- PTT TPIT Data Center and Office, 11th floor PTT PLC, Bangkok
- · Abbott Office, Muang Thai Pattara Building.
- YARA office, The Emporium 22nd floor, Bangkok
- Nike Shop, Siam Square, Bangkok
- CIMB Thai Branch, Surattani
- Bank of Ayudhya, Queen Sirikitiya Convention Center, Bangkok
- TMB Branch, The Mall Ngamwongwan, Nontaburi

Oct 2008 to Dec 2008

Sino-Thai Engineering and Construction, Rayong, Thailand

Site Engineer

 Site Engineer at Banchang fabrication yard for main pipe rack module for PLUTO LNG PHASE I Project

TRAINING

CTCI (Thailand) CO.,Ltd:

- PDMS: Piping Design Management System
- PDS: Piping Design System
- PMCS: Piping Material Control System
- Piping Material Specification
- OHSE: Occupational, Hygiene, Safety and Environment Committee
- Pipe Support Design
- Loop Expansion Calculation
- Nozzle Thermal Movement Calculation

Optional

Current Address: 688/1318, 19th floor, Building A, Supalai Pak Srinakarin

Condominium, Nongbon, Prawat, Bangkok Thailand, 10260

Home Address: 106/59, Mahidol Rd., Nonghoi, Muang, Chiangmai, Thailand,

5000

Mobile Phone: 085-9341997,

E-mail: <u>bangic@hotmail.com</u>, bordin.p@outlook.com

Marital Status: single

Military Status: Reserve officers training corps course(ROTC)

Engineering License: License for Professional Practice, Associate Mechanical

Engineer

Driving License: Personal cars. ID. No. 47004003

Campus activities:

1) Volunteer Club

- Camp management Club vice-president
- 2) Auto challenge Club
 - 3rd Place in an innovation field for adjusting auto gear changing system in TSAE Auto Challenge 2006
- 3) Faculty's Football club
 - 3rd place in CMU freshman games
- 4) Faculty's Music club Club's member